（左門）姫様は　すでに死んでいる。
The princess is already dead.
（不破真広）どういうことだ？
What's going on?
（左門・通信）
姫様　そこは　我々にとって→
Princess...
Your world is two years in our past.
２年前の世界です。
（左門）
魔法によって　今現在と２年前の→
With the power of magic, the present has been connected to your time on that island
（通信）その島が　時間を越えて
つながっているのです。
by traveling through time two years into the past.
（葉風）時間を越えて!?
Traveling through time?
ピシャーン！（雷鳴）
Episode 9
Boyfriend
ボゥン　ボゥン　ボゥン！
バシューー！
ドシューー！
ドカーーン！
ドカン！　ドカン　ドカン！
（兵士）人？
A person?
（夏村）鎖部夏村→
I, Kusaribe Natsumura,
推参なり。
am here to pay an unannounced visit.
（滝川吉野）時間を越えて？
Traveling through time?
So you're saying
つまり　今こうして
俺らと話しているのは→
the Hakaze we're speaking to now is the Hakaze from two years ago.
２年前の葉風で　今現在の葉風は
そこにある骨だってのか？
And that the current Hakaze is that bunch of bones?
そうだ。
だったら→
That is correct.
In that case,
how can this let me connect to the her two years in the past?
なんで　これが　２年の時を越えて
つながったりしたんだ？
それは　鎖部の魔法によって
作られた人形同士が→
That doll, a talisman made with Kusaribe magic,
共鳴して通信を行う魔具。→
connects to another similar doll for communication.
姫様の持っていた
もう一方の人形は→
I imagine the doll the princess used two years ago
２年の歳月が流れる間に
無人島で→
was destroyed at some point.
朽ち果ててしまったのだろう。
ちっ！
So,
で　今現在
つながれる相手がいないならと→
because this doll couldn't find another doll to connect to in the present,
時間をさかのぼって
つながれる人形を探したのか。
you're saying it looked through time, to connect to the one two years ago?
Precisely.
（左門）そのとおり。
It's true...
（心の声）≪そうだ…
普通に会話するときに→
In normal conversation,
we had no reason to mention the current year.
いちいち　西暦なんか確認しない≫
Even if we'd discussed dates,
≪日付の話をしても
きっちり２年ずれてるから→
we're exactly two years ahead, so we couldn't have noticed.
分からなかったんだ≫
（葉風）バカな…　ありえん！→
Impossible...
Inconceivable!
左門！　堅実が信条の貴様が→
Samon!
You live by reliable, conservative principles.
私を殺すなどという危険を
冒すはずがない！→
You would never take a risk like killing me.
私がいなければ→
Without me there,
what will you do if the Tree of Exodus's revival fails?
絶園の樹の復活に失敗したとき
どうする気だ!?
姫様　堅実な私とて
あなたが相手となれば→
Princess,
as conservative as I may be, if I'm going up against you,
大きな賭けも打ちます。
おそらく姫様には→
even I would need to assume some risk.
To you, it may appear to be only four months of preparation.
４か月程度にしか
思えていないのでしょうが→
堅実ゆえに　準備に
２年以上もかけたのです。
But we have been working carefully on this for two years.
Additionally,
それに　この骨→
Juunichiro has confirmed that this is your skeleton.
（通信）潤一郎も
姫様のものだと認めました。
That's right...
≪そうだ　人形を入れたボトル…≫
It was always strange
that the bottle with the doll
washed up in Japan within four months.
≪あれが　数か月で　日本に
流れ着いたとするのも　おかしい≫
Given estimates of this island's position,
≪この島があると思われる
熱帯の海域からして→
漂着時期が
早すぎるのではないか？≫
relative to Japan, it arrived too soon.
Why didn't I guess that two years could have passed?
（葉風）≪２年くらい過ぎていると
なぜ思わなかった？→
Did I overestimate my own luck?
自分の強運に　うぬぼれたのか？≫
（葉風）では
やはり　私は死んでいるのか？
In that case,
am I really dead?
ここは　貴様たちにとって
２年前の時と場所なのか？
Is this all really two years in your past?
こうして話している姫様は→
Speaking to you now, Princess,
is like an illusion to us.
我々にとって　幻のようなもの。→
生きていても死んでいる。→
Although you are alive, you are also dead.
その島は　あなたにとって
時間の檻なのです。→
For you, that island is a cage within time.
姫様　あなたの負けです。
Princess, you have lost.
ボゥン！
（宇津井）
個人の防御壁は　限界が近いはず。
His personal barrier should be nearing its limit.
If we can exhaust it, it will fall.
消耗させれば　すぐに破れる。
Men, stay on guard!
一人と油断するな！
撃ちまくれ～！
Keep shooting!
ボゥン！　ボゥン！
ドシュ　ドシュ　ドシュ！
≪あと１００メートル≫
A hundred more meters...
ドシュ　ドシュ　ドシュ　ドシュ！
≪５０≫
Fifty...
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹…。
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree...
バシュー！
はっ！
ドカーン！
やったか!?
Did we do it?
始まりにありし　はじまりの樹→
Tree that has existed since the beginning, Tree of Genesis.
Hear my words, and grant my wish.
我が言葉において聞き届けよ！
（宇津井）せっ　戦車が…。
The tank...
Return! Return! Return! Return! Return! Return! Return!
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ　戻れ→
戻れ　戻れ→
戻れ　戻れ…。
（哲馬）≪我らに　攻撃魔法はない≫
Our practice does not include offensive magic.
≪だが　兵器に直接　触れて→
But by touching the weapon
and offering it to the Tree of Genesis,
はじまりの樹に
供物として捧げれば→
it is possible to reduce it to ash within seconds.
一瞬で　それを塵にできる≫
ドシューー！
ドカーーン！
And he can use the power
（哲馬）≪その供物によって
新たな防御フィールドを展開すれば→
of that offering to create another defensive barrier,
砲弾の１０や２０は
また受けきれる！≫
allowing him to withstand ten or twenty more rounds!
（通信士・通信）結界内より出現した
目標Ａ　撃破ならず！→
Failed to neutralize target that emerged from the barrier!
各部隊　混乱しています！
The troops are in disarray!
We briefed the troops on the extent of their abilities.
（早河）≪ヤツらの能力に関しての
報告書は提出してあった≫
（通信）右側面だ！　３時方向！
（通信）どこだ!?
To the right, around 3 o'clock!
Where is he?
≪だが　人間でありながら
あれほどの機動力と防御力を→
However, even though he is human, his superior mobility and defense
併せ持つ目標に
そうそう対応はできんか…≫
pose a significant challenge to our men.
Young men, your journey has ended.
（左門）少年たちよ
お前たちの旅も終わった。→
There is no reason for us to be opposed any longer.
もはや
我らが対立する理由はなかろう。
悪いようにはせん。
ただ　鎖部の長としては→
I have no further quarrel with you.
However, as head of the Kusaribe,
I cannot permit you to continue using our magic.
お前たちが　これ以上　外界で
魔法を使うことは許可できん。→
If you leave the talismans and depart this place,
魔具を置いて
立ち去るというのなら→
身の安全は保障しよう。
I guarantee that you will not be harmed.
≪確かに　旅は終わったな≫
Our journey has, indeed, ended.
Ultimately, it was impossible for us
≪そもそも　世界の命運なんて→
to carry the fate of the world.
僕らに背負えやしなかったんだ≫
残念だったな　葉風。
Too bad, Hakaze.
（通信）まあ　骨になってるんなら
しかたねぇ。　悪く思うな。
Well, there's nothing we can do if you're just bones.
Don't hold it against me.
I don't expect your pity.
貴様の情けなど期待しておらん。
好きにしろ。
Do as you will.
Yeah, you can just die there.
ああ　そこで勝手に死んでろ。
じゃあな　葉風。
So long, Hakaze.
≪ふっ…　そうだ　それでいい≫
Good.
That is what you should do.
さて　鎖部左門。
うん？
All right, Kusaribe Samon...
I still have plans for this thing.
俺はまだ
こいつを使う気があるぜ？
Eh?
えっ!?
何故!?
For what purpose?
姫様が　こちらに戻らなければ
お前たちも負けであろう！→
If the princess cannot return,
that means you have lost, as well!
If you were to use that talisman to unleash the Tree of Exodus,
ひとたび　その魔具を発動させて
絶園の樹を狂わせれば→
no one will be able to stop it.
誰も　その破壊を止められん！
世界が　それで終わるぞ！
The world will end there!
Hey, now...
おいおい　俺が
いつ　世界のことを気にかけたよ？
When did I ever say that I cared about the world?
世界が　どうにかなって困るのは
お前らだけだろ？
If something happens to the world,
you're the only ones who'll be upset.
≪この少年…≫
This boy...
Let's make a deal, Kusaribe Samon.
取り引きだ　鎖部左門。
If Hakaze can't do it, I'll have you grant my wish.
葉風がダメなら
お前に俺の望みをかなえてもらう。
And if you can't, I really don't give a crap about this world.
できないっていうなら
もとより　こんな世界→
どうなってもいいからな。
あぁ…。
≪そうか…　真広は
最初から考えていたはずだ→
Of course...
From the start, Mahiro must have been considering this.
What he'd do if he couldn't rely on Ms. Hakaze anymore.
葉風さんが　当てにならなく
なったときのことを≫
この魔具を手に　ここへ来た時点で
俺は　葉風とお前→
Bringing this talisman with me
has put me in the position to deal with either Hakaze or you.
どっちとも取り引きできる立場に
なったんだよ。
葉風が使えねぇなら→
If Hakaze didn't work out,
I never had any problem switching sides.
お前に乗り換えたって
全然かまわなかったのさ。
≪でも　真広→
But, Mahiro...
Are you really okay with abandoning Ms. Hakaze this way?
葉風さんを
こんな形で見捨てていいのか？≫
≪なんという…
なんという少年だ≫
This boy...
That audacity of his...
≪大義も情もなく　姫様を見捨て→
He deserted the princess without hesitation or sentiment.
ただ己の欲望のためだけに
世界を脅かそうというのか!?≫
He's willing to risk the world for the sake of his own desire?
So what'll it be, Kusaribe Samon?
さあ　どうする？　鎖部左門。
俺の指は軽いぜ？
I'm a trigger-happy guy.
≪はったりではない。→
He isn't bluffing.
If I try to take the talisman,
魔具を奪おうとすれば
必ず引き金を引く。→
he will no doubt pull that trigger.
At this rate, he might well do it regardless.
そうでなくても
はずみで引かせる可能性もある。→
これも
はじまりの樹の理のうちか？≫
Is this also the reasoning of the Tree of Genesis?
≪いや　あの少年も
姫様を切り捨てた≫
No, that boy deserted the princess.
≪姫様の勝つ目はない≫
There's no way for the princess to win!
≪落ち着いて対処すればいい≫
I need but deal with this calmly,
within the limit of acceptable error.
≪誤差の範囲内だ≫
What is your wish?
お前の望みはなんだ？
私も知る必要があろう。
I suppose I shall need to know.
１年前　俺の妹が　誰かに殺された。
One year ago,
someone murdered my younger sister.
俺は　その犯人を捜している。
I'm looking for the one responsible,
so that I can kill him.
見つけて　そいつを殺すためにな。
Are you asking me to use magic to find the killer?
（左門）
魔法で　その犯人を見つけろと？
Exactly.
そうだ。
そいつを　この手で殺せれば→
If I can kill him with my own hands,
お前に
この魔具を素直にくれてやるよ。
I have no problem giving this talisman to you.
≪犯人捜し…
思ったよりは　常識的な要求か≫
Searching for the killer..
A much more reasonable request than I expected.
だが　見つけるのには
時間がかかるぞ。→
However, it will take some time to find him.
殺人現場は　どこだ？
そこから　探査魔法を…。
Where is the scene of the crime?
From there, I can use a search—
その必要はねぇ。
There's no need for that.
Hakaze's magic filtered through the possibilities.
葉風の魔法で
ある程度　絞り込めてる。
The killer
犯人は　鎖部一族の誰かだ。
is someone from the Kusaribe clan!
ん!?
あんたなら　すぐに捜せるだろ。
You should be able to find them in no time.
一族の者が犯人というのは
確かか？
You're certain that someone from the clan is responsible?
葉風の魔法の結果だ。
That's what Hakaze's magic said.
葉風が
そんなうそをつく理由があるか？
Would she have any reason to lie?
（左門）なかろうな。→
Unlikely.
I can think of no motive for her to deceive you over the results of her investigation.
それほど　特殊な探査結果を
偽る理由や方法など思いつかん。
Then get with it
じゃあ　妹を…→
and identify the one who killed my sister, Aika.
愛花を殺したヤツを
すぐに特定しろ。
And bring him to me alive!
そして
生きたまま　俺の前に転がせ。
That is my wish.
それが　俺の望みだ！
≪私欲で　殺人を犯し→
Using magic to commit murder
あまつさえ
犯行に魔法を利用したとすれば→
for their own personal gain
is an unforgivable crime.
許し難い大罪≫
≪たとえ　一族の者とはいえ→
While he may be of our clan,
turning the killer over to him in exchange for the talisman
大罪を犯した者を引き渡して
魔具が手に入るのなら→
is a negligible price.
これは　安すぎる代償…≫
（左門）分かった。→
Very well.
I will grant your wish.
お前の要求に応じよう。
ふっ。
その妹が殺されたのは　いつだ？
When was your sister killed?
１年前の１１月２３日。
Last year, November 23rd.
哲馬　苦しいところ　すまん。→
Tetsuma, I apologize for disturbing you.
I want you to look into something at once.
至急　調べてほしいことがある。
最優先だ。
This takes top priority.
≪あと少しだ…≫
Just a little longer...
≪あと少しで　俺の辻褄が合う≫
A little longer,
and the world will make sense for me again!
≪ああ　すごいよ　真広≫
Yeah, you really are amazing, Mahiro.
Absolutely amazing.
≪お前は　すごいよ≫
Countless people have died,
≪たくさんの人が死んで
魔法と樹が　世界を揺るがして→
the world has been shaken by trees and magic,
時間さえ　ねじれる
ひどい有様の中で→
even time itself has been twisted,
but you'll still keep pushing your logic forward, for your wish's sake.
お前だけは
お前の理屈を押し切って→
望みをかなえてしまうんだな≫
≪でも真広　これは悲劇だ≫
But, Mahiro, this is a tragedy.
A tragedy!
≪悲劇だよ≫
I don't have the power or right to stop this, but...
≪僕に　それを止める力も資格も
ありはしないけど…≫
葉風さん　吉野です。
Ms. Hakaze, this is Yoshino.
（通信）今　真広と左門の取り引きが
成立しました。
The deal between Mahiro and Samon has been finalized.
（葉風）そうか。
I see...
That would mean the checkmate was actually at my expense.
これで　私の方が
完全に詰まされたというわけか…。
（通信）
そう簡単に諦めていいんですか？
Will you really give up so easily?
葉風さんが正しいなら
絶園の樹の復活で→
If you're correct, Ms. Hakaze,
the Tree of Exodus is going to destroy the world, right?
世界は滅びるんでしょう？
だが　手がない。
It's out of my hands.
私は　そちらの時間で
もう死んでいる。→
In your time, I'm already deceased.
（通信）
一時的に　復活を止められても→
Even if I can stop it temporarily,
その後
左門を阻める者がいないのだ。→
there will eventually be no one to stop Samon.
私が　そちらに戻れないと
決まったとき→
As soon as it was clear that I could not return,
all possibilities disappeared.
すべての道は消えた。→
真広が　私を見捨てても
文句は言えん。
I cannot complain that Mahiro chose to desert me.
ここで　真広のように
「ハムレット」のセリフでも→
If I could quote Hamlet the way Mahiro does at times like this,
引用できれば
少しは格好がつくのだが→
I would be much cooler.
Sadly, nothing comes to mind.
（通信）
あいにく　何も思い浮かばん。
This is definitely not the time to be quoting that tragedy.
こんなとき　あんな悲劇から
引用するものじゃありませんよ。
僕も　よく愛花ちゃんに…。
Aika always used to—
（愛花・回想）((天と地の間には→
There are more things
in heaven and earth, than are dreamt of in your philosophy.
お前の哲学では
思いもよらない出来事があるぞ…))
（愛花）
((ここは　そんな場所ですね))
Isn't this place just like that?
((また「ハムレット」？))
（愛花）((ええ))
Hamlet again?
Indeed.
((それ　やめようよ))
Let's stop that.
Why? It's a classic.
（愛花）
((どうしてです？　名作ですよ？))
((あれ　復讐にこだわるせいで→
That story is a tragedy about Hamlet's mother,
母親も恋人も　そのお兄ちゃんも→
his lover, and his lover's older brother
who dies due to his obsession with revenge.
みんな死んじゃう悲劇の話だよ？))
((だいたい　ハムレット自身も→
And Hamlet himself dies in a duel with the older brother.
恋人のお兄ちゃんと決闘して
死んじゃうし→
縁起悪すぎるって))
It's too unlucky.
((私たちに置き換えると→
Then, were we to relate this to our lives,
this would be where you and Mahiro would kill each other because of me.
私のせいで　真広と吉野さんが
殺し合う展開ですね))
And I'm saying that that future is not actually impossible.
((だから　それ　部分的に
ありそうな未来なんだって…))
（愛花）((「ハムレット」からの引用が
よくないというのなら→
If you dislike quotes from Hamlet,
同じ復讐の話でも→
why don't I quote from another story of revenge,
but one in which everyone lives happily ever after?
最後は　皆が幸せになる物語から
引用しましょうか))
((これも
シェイクスピアの作品で→
It is another of Shakespeare's plays,
孤島の魔法使いの物語です))
and it's about a sorcerer on an island.
A mage on an island?
((復讐の話なのに
みんなが幸せになるって…))
A story about revenge, but everyone lives happily ever after?
What's this story called?
((それ　なんてタイトル？))
It's called
The Tempest.
≪なんだ？　なんで
急に　こんなことを思い出す？≫
What's going on?
Why am I remembering that now?
≪復讐　孤島　魔法使い…≫
Revenge, an island, a mage.
Is this all coincidence?
≪これは偶然!?≫
≪もしかして　愛花ちゃん…→
Is it possible, Aika,
to make this story not end in tragedy?
これを
悲劇じゃない物語にできるのか？≫
≪僕は
そのために　ここにいる？≫
Is that the reason I'm here?
≪葉風さんを　孤島から
ここに戻す道があるとでも…≫
Is there a way for me to save Ms. Hakaze from that island?
I'll give it a shot, Aika.
≪やってみるよ　愛花ちゃん≫
≪空気の精霊か
それとも　醜い怪物か…≫
I don't know if the character in that story
≪あの物語の登場人物の
誰なのかは分からないけど→
is an air sprite or a hideous monster,
これが　僕に与えられた
役だというのなら…≫
but if this is the role given to me...
ん？
ごめん　真広。
I'm sorry, Mahiro.
ガン！
なんのまねだよ!?
The hell are you doing?!
Thought I'd borrow that talisman for a sec.
ちょっと　その魔具を
渡してもらおうと思ってね！
ガン！
Where'd you get your hands on something like that?
そんなもん
どこで手に入れたんだよ？
Would you believe me if I said they were cheap through mail order?
通販で安くって言ったら信じるか？
What is this?
≪なんだ？
何がどうなっている!?≫
What's going on?
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹→
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree,
我が言葉において聞き届けよ！
hear my words, and grant my wish!
≪これ以上　訳の分からぬ展開など
たまらんぞ！≫
I will not allow things to become even more uncertain!
ドカッ！
いいかげんにしろ！　ん!?
That's enough!
（左門）ふん！
キン！
Don't you dare harm Yoshino!
吉野に手を出すな！
バカを言うな！
Don't be foolish!
お前が　魔具を奪われては
こちらも困る！
If the talisman is stolen from you, I will also be at a disadvantage!
Shut the hell up!
うるせぇ！　お前がどいてろ！
You stay out of this!
吉野…。
くっ！
Yoshino...
≪何故　こんなときに→
How did I end up in the middle of a fight between children?
私が　子供のケンカの
仲裁をするはめに…≫
これで２０…。
ガキン！
That makes twenty.
So it appears that if two barriers collide,
（山本）やっぱり　魔法の
フィールド同士がぶつかれば→
はじき飛ばすくらいは
できるみたいね。
I can at least repel you.
Who are you?
何奴!?
（山本）姓は山本　名はエヴァンジェリン→
Last name: Yamamoto.
First name: Evangeline.
Otherwise known as Fräulein Yamamoto.
人呼んで　フロイライン山本。
無職の２８歳。
Twenty-eight and unemployed.
推参なり！
And here to pay an unannounced visit.
お前の連れは
何を考えている!?
What is he thinking?
何が目的だ!?
って質問だが？
What is his motive?!
Well?
Why did we come here?
僕らは　なんのために　ここに来た。
ああ？
僕らは　１年前　理不尽に殺された
女の子のために→
The reason we came should have been for the sake of a girl who was unjustly killed.
ここに来たはずだ。
なのに　僕らが　同じように→
But is it really all right for us to desert
another girl in the same unjust position?
理不尽な目に遭わされた女の子を
見捨てていいのか？
このまま死なせていいのか？
Are you really okay with letting her die?
復讐のためとはいえ　お前は→
Be it for the sake of revenge,
will you really allow such a tragic ending?
そんな悲劇の結末を許すのか!?
ちっ…。
お前が以前　果実が飛んだ町で→
At one of the cities where the fruit had flown,
助けなくてもいい女の子を
助けたのは→
you saved a girl you didn't have to save.
Wasn't it because you couldn't bear such an ending?
それが耐えられなかったからじゃ
ないのか!?
しかたねぇだろ。
I don't have a choice.
その人形の向こうにいるのは
２年前の葉風だ。
The Hakaze on the other side of that doll is the Hakaze of the past.
現在の葉風は
そこに吊られてる骨だぞ。
The present Hakaze is the collection of bones over there.
It doesn't matter what we do. She's already dead!
（通信）俺らが何しようと
もう死んでるんだよ！
So my striking up a deal to kill the murderer is within reason!
だったら　こいつと取り引きして→
犯人だけでも　ぶっ殺すってのは
理にかなってる。
それなら　復讐ができて→
Then if there were a way to get your revenge and save Ms. Hakaze,
葉風さんを救う手段が
あるっていうんなら→
もう一度　葉風さん側に
つく気はあるってことか？
you'd be willing to return to Ms. Hakaze's side?
What is he saying?
≪何を言いだす!?≫
骨になった人間を
救えるわけねぇだろ。
There's no way to save someone who's just a bunch of bones.
魔法でも
死人は生き返らねぇんだ！
Even with magic, you can't revive the dead!
知ってる。　死者は生き返らない。
I know that.
The dead won't come back to life.
愛花ちゃんも生き返らない。
Aika won't come back to life.
でも僕には　２年前の空間にいる
という葉風さんを→
But I'm prepared to prove
that there's a way to reclaim Ms. Hakaze
from her dimension two years in the past.
ここに生きて戻せると立証する
準備がある。
≪よもや　あの少年…≫
He can't mean...
たとえ　そうだとしても→
Even if that's true,
じきに　愛花を殺した犯人が
分かるってのに→
if I'm about to learn Aika's killer's identity,
なんで　今更　葉風の側に
つかなきゃならないんだ。
why should I bother going back to Hakaze's side?
No matter how you look at it, there's nothing in it for me.
どう考えても
俺にメリットはねぇだろ。
≪そうだ　それでいい≫
Yes, that's right.
メリットはある。
うん？
But there is something.
真広
こちらの側につくというなら→
Mahiro, if you'll switch back to this side,
お前に　愛花ちゃんの彼氏が
誰だったか教えてやる。
I'll tell you the identity of Aika's boyfriend.
≪彼氏…　だと!?≫
Boyfriend?
でまかせ言ってんじゃねぇぞ。
You'd better not be making things up.
こんな状況で
でまかせなんて言うと思うか？
As if I'd make things up at a time like this.
本当に知ってんだな？
You really know who it was?
Well, of course, since it was me.
≪そりゃ　その彼氏って
僕のことだし≫
ああ　知ってる。　でも真広→
Yes, I do.
But, Mahiro,
僕の話に乗らないかぎり→
unless you agree to my terms,
誰かは　一生　教えない。
I will never tell you who it was.
You'll be left ignorant of who it was forever.
お前は　誰か知らないまま
一生　悩むことになるぞ。
Wait.
≪待て…　彼氏がなんだ!?≫
Who cares about some boyfriend?
Why are you torn by this? Unbelievable!
≪どうして迷う!?
ありえんだろう！≫
簡単に　取り引きには乗れねぇぞ。
I won't agree that easily.
骨になってる葉風を救うなんて
普通に考えりゃ不可能だ。
If you think about it logically, it's impossible to restore Hakaze if she's just bones.
これから　それを立証する。
I will prove to you that it's possible.
その方法に納得できれば
葉風さんにつくか？
If I manage to convince you,
will you rejoin Ms. Hakaze's side?
And if I do, you'll tell me who Aika's boyfriend was, right?
ついたら
愛花の彼氏が誰か教えるんだな？
If we can bring Ms. Hakaze back, I'll tell you.
葉風さんを
ここに戻せたら教えるよ。
ふっ…
いいぜ　その不可能　解いてみせろ。
Fine.
Make the impossible possible.
Hey! What are you saying?
おい　何を言っている！
今になって　何を立証すると…。
What could he possibly say at this point?!
お前の話じゃ
葉風は　とうに死んでるんだろ？
According to you, Hakaze's dead, right?
なんで焦る？
くっ…。
Why are you panicking?
愛花を殺した犯人が
連れてこられるまで→
It's going to take time for you to get Aika's murderer for me.
時間があるんだ。
暇潰しには　ちょうどいいだろ。
This will be good for killing time.
（左門）分かった。
その余興　つきあってやろう。
Very well, I agree to those terms.
吉野　話は聞いてやる。
Yoshino, I'll listen to what you have to say.
ただし→
However...
愛花を殺したヤツが
ここに連れてこられるまでだ。
Only until Aika's killer is brought here.
If you can't convince me by then, no deal.
それまでに納得できなきゃ
お前との取り引きはなしだ。
ああ　かまわない。
Yeah, that's fine.
≪信じられん…≫
I can't believe this...
The whole situation has turned on its head
≪彼氏というひと言だけで→
状況が　ひっくり返るとは…≫
just with the word "boyfriend."
≪この世界の理は
どうなっている？≫
What is happening to the logic of this world?
≪この世界のあらゆる事象
あらゆる生き物→
All of this world's events,
all of the living creatures,
そして　海　空　雲　風　太陽…≫
as well as the ocean, sky, clouds, wind, and sun...
≪それらすべてを
天秤にかけてすら→
All of that has been put on a scale, and has all been outweighed
釣り合わぬまでに
愛花という少女は…≫
by this girl named Aika.
じゃあ→
All right.
Here's my theory.
立証を始めるぞ。
kimi to miteta nagareboshi oikakete
Chasing the shooting star that we saw together
Reaching this place all alone
hitori bocchi konna toko made kiteta
Hiding the feelings I wanted to express to you
kinou kimi ni ienakatta kimochi o
kotoba no naka kakusu no
within words
tooku hanarete itemo douka todokimasu you ni
No matter how far we are separated,
please let it reach you
kono michi no saki ni matsu unmei nante
The fate waiting for us down this road
is not yet known
ima wa mada
dare mo mada
shiranai kedo
by anyone
To the future drawn by numbed fingers
kajikan da yubisaki de egaita mirai he
With you we can make it
kimi to nara ikerutte
nee sonna ki ga shiteta nda
That's what I feel
kitto
with certainty
So things will go exactly as we'd originally planned...
最初から　俺らの計画どおり。
（左門）鎖部一族が
三代にわたって試行を重ね→
The Kusaribe clan spent three generations
painstakingly constructing this.
ようやく編み出した。
（山本）名前を聞かせて　魔法使い。
Tell me your name, mage.
（潤一郎）
ほら　お菓子もあるんだよ。
See? I have snacks, too.
You're surprisingly underhanded.
（葉風）貴様　意外に性格悪いな。
（夏村）大したものだ。
Impressive.
まっとうな論理です！
（左門）詭弁だ！
It's a valid theory!
It's a logical fallacy!
Episode 10
How to Make
a Time Machine